Jay Massey

jaymassey98@gmail.com - linkedin.com/in/jay-massey - Worthing, West Sussex

Software engineer with a passion for embedded systems, alongside a keen interest in making complex designs both generalised and more efficient. 9+ months of industry experience, with 8+ years writing code in general, as an individual and in teams. Various related projects are available at https://jaymassey98.github.io/portfolio.

Work Experience

Thales

Crawley, West Sussex 09/2021 – Present

Embedded Software Engineer

- Worked on ISO 9001 certified communication devices, such as MSN8200 3G ALE HF radios.
- Utilised MISRA C notions / C++ STL, for 32-bit ARMs with FreeRTOS on Linux / Windows.
- Optimised legacy code by restructuring 40+ hardcoded designs into one generic, reusable system.
- Enabled easy to maintain code by applying consistent value checks via system configuration files.
- Structured this way allowed easy repurposing, enabling cost reductions for future audio projects.
- Interpreted, designed, and deployed code, following a streamlined software development process.
- Assisted in RF modelling via digital signal processing in MATLAB / Simulink to generate code.
- Overhauled testing with scripts to assess all of the billions of radio combinations automatically.
- Integrated Git software version control into build tools such as Xilinx Vitis and Visual Studio.

Peacocks

Duty Manager

Hove, East Sussex 11/2016 – 04/2019

- Led a fast-fashion sales retail team for 2+ days a week, during my superiors' days off for a year.
- Promoted from key holder after demonstrating excellent store knowledge and leadership skills.
- Managed employee training for new recruits, offering them continuous advice and mentorship.
- Supervised teams of 4 8 people to deliver consistent KPI's and high standard customer service.
- Selected to merchandise other stores, such as Brighton and London, after achieving high targets.

Education

University of Brighton

BSc (Hons) Computer Science – 2:1

Brighton, East Sussex 09/2017 – 09/2020

- Agile & Scrum Managed projects effectively through a variety of agile model methodologies.
- Connections Transferred IoT data over Bluetooth, USB, and Wi-Fi, via UART and TCP/IP.
- **Circuit Design** Designed digital and analogue circuits using 74xx components and 555 timers.
- **PCB Design** Produced detailed PCB layouts from designed circuitry and self-made schematics.
- **RF Concepts** Explored various Rx / Tx concepts, such as noise, carrier waves and modulation.

Also exposed to assembly, calculus, DevOps, Jenkins (for CD/CI), Jira, Kanban, Python, SQL, and VMware.

Previous Education

09/2011 - 09/2017

Electronics AS (B), Mathematics AS (B), Physics AS (C) – 13 GCSEs, 6 A's, 5 B's, 2 C's, incl. 2 A's in English.

Personal

Additional Skills – Driving; entertaining; first aid trained; live presenting; Microsoft Office, especially Excel. **General Interests** – Bouldering; designing; gaming; ice skating; philosophy; strength training; overclocking.